By the decision of Ying Zheng, the king that wished to unite all of China,
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
天下統一の道を行く王 嬴政(えいせい)のもと
the State of Qin began its invasion of the State of Wei.
秦国(しんこく)は 魏国(ぎこく)へと侵攻した
The enemy blocking their way is the legendary Great General, Lian Po.
立ちはだかる敵は
伝説の大将軍 廉頗(れんぱ)
Young generals take on this relentless battlefield in hopes of rendering great military achievements.
若き将たちは 大いなる武功を狙い
この苛烈な戦場に挑む
The Caliber of a General
（兵士）アア… こいつら…
These guys are...
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
生真面目さゆえ 爆発的な力を
持たないといわれる魏国兵だが
Although the State of Wei soldiers are said to not have explosive power because they are too serious,
the appearance of Lian Po
廉頗の出現は
彼らのタガを外させた
made them go mad.
Kill them, kill them!
（魏兵）殺せ殺せ！
Lord Bi!
（部下Ａ）壁(へき)さま！
（部下Ｂ）
壁さま！ 魏国の歩兵のあの勢い…
Lord Bi!
That vigor the State of Wei Soldiers have...
（壁）落ち着け… 落ち着くんだ
Calm down. Think.
At times like this, a general has to be cool-headed...
こういうときこそ
将たる者は冷静に…
崖の上は こちらが制したまま
The soldiers on that cliff are keeping us back...
Right now, the State of Qin Army has the advantage on this enclosed land!
この囲地の利は
秦国軍が手にしたままだ
The only part of the cliffs we lost is that area that Lian Po took.
崖の上を取られたのは
廉頗が現れた あの一部だけだ
I see! The reason why Lian Po was able to get here so fast when he was supposed to be at the headquarters,
そうか！ 本陣にいたはずの廉頗が
ここへ来た早さ
and the reason we didn't sense him coming...
そして こちらが それを
察知できなかったことからして…
Lian Po Army 1,000
Jiang Yan Army 7,000
Bi Army 4,000
Wang Jian Army 6,000
is because even at a high estimate, his army probably only numbers 1,000!
（壁）
恐らく あの部隊の数は
多めに見積もっても
And if we consider how many casualties there have been thus far,
そして ここまでの
死傷者を考えれば
今の戦力は
秦国軍 １万に対し
right now the situation is around 10,000 in the State of Qin Army and 8,000 in the State of Wei Army who are still alive.
魏国軍８０００と
いうところか
In terms of numbers, there isn't much of a difference.
数の上では
ほとんど差はない
The other side has high morale due to the appearance of Lian Po,
向こうには
廉頗出現による士気の高さがあるが
こちらには
囲地という絶対の地の利がある
but we have the definite terrain advantage in using this enclosed land!
Depending on how we fight here, we may even be able to take down Lian Po...!
戦い方しだいでは あの廉頗を…
Jiang Yan is fleeing towards his allies!
（側近Ａ）
姜燕(きょうえん)が友軍のほうへ逃げます！
Leave them be.
（王翦(おうせん)）放っておけ
The pressing matter is the poor
coordination of the inner army.
（王翦）
それより 中の軍がバラバラだ
Send out all of the commanders and have them form units.
各将を散らして 隊形を組ませよ
（側近Ａ）はっ！
Yes, sir!
（廉頗）
まずは 乱れた軍の整理を始めたか
So first they're organizing their scattered armies?
（廉頗）ハハハッ… さてさて
そこから どう動く？ 王翦
Okay, so what are you going to do next, Wang Jian?
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）廉頗にとって―
Lian Po's attention was drawn to how Wang Jian was acting.
ここからの王翦の挙動は
興味を引くところであった
両軍の数は ほぼ互角
The two armies were about even in number.
囲地という
絶好の地の利がある秦国軍に対し
Against the State of Qin Army, having the severe land advantage,
was the State of Wei Army with their morale at a maximum.
士気最高潮の魏国軍
軍略家が腕を見せるにあたっては
この上ない材料が そろっていた
With these excellent resources at hand, it was time for strategists to show off their skill.
All units assembled!
（側近Ａ）各隊 整いました！
（王翦）うむ… こちらの主軸が
削られぬことだけ注意せよ
Pay close attention that our lynchpins are not curtailed.
（側近Ｂ）分かっております
Understood.
How will Wang Jian, a man said to be on par with Wang Qi and the other Six Great Generals, manage this situation?
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）王騎(おうき)に
六大将軍級と評された王翦は―
果たして
これをどう料理してくるのか
Lian Po has been trying to measure what degree of a military commander Wang Jian is on this battlefield.
廉頗は
王翦が どの程度の武将なのか―
この戦場で
測ろうとしていたのである
しかし 王翦は
そんな廉頗の期待を見事に裏切った
But Wang Jian has betrayed Lian Po's expectations in spectacular fashion.
では…
Now then...
all units, retreat.
全軍 退却だ
クッ… 撤退だと？
Retreat?!
Why?! This was our big chance!
（側近Ａ）
せっかくの好機に なぜ…
知らぬ！
我らは しんがりだ　気を抜くな！
I don't know!
We're the rear guard! Don't lose focus!
（王翦）悪いな 廉頗
Sorry, Lian Po.
I am not interested in battles except for those I am certain to win.
私は 絶対に勝つ戦以外 興味はない
フッ… なるほどのぅ
I see.
Kill them!
（魏兵）殺せ！ 逃がすな！
Don't let them get away!
（側近Ａ）壁さま もっと前へ！
Lord Bi! Get further ahead!
ダメだ！ 歩兵を見捨てるな！
騎馬は歩兵の援護を！
No! We can't abandon the foot soldiers!
Send mounted soldiers to cover the foot soldiers!
（側近Ｂ）
ム… ムチャです！ 後ろに もう…
W-We can't! The rear is already...
I do not understand.
（姜燕）腑(ふ)に落ちませぬ
（姜燕）肩透かしをされて
なぜ喜んでおられるのか
Why are you so happy after a missed opportunity?
Happy?
喜んでおるか
（姜燕）そう見えます
That is how it appears.
ハハハッ…
ならば そうなのじゃろう
Well, maybe I am.
Yan Jiang, have you ever fought with any of the State of Qin Six Great Generals?
姜燕… うぬは秦国六大将軍
誰と戦ったことがある？
六大将軍ですか
Six Great Generals?
Bai Qi, Wang He, Wang Qi, and Liao.
王齕(おうこつ)…
王騎…
摎(きょう)… この４人です
Those four.
Which would you say was the most heated?
どいつが いちばん熱かった？
（姜燕）熱い？
Heated?
私の場合は摎ですね
In my case, Liao, I suppose.
互いに攻め重視なので
毎回 両軍ともに 万の犠牲が
We both had heavy attacks, so every time, there were ten thousand sacrifices on both sides.
ハハハッ… あやつの攻めは
殊更ひどかったのぅ
That one's attacks were intentionally brutal.
But which would you say was the hardest one to fight?
では いちばん
やりづらかったのは どいつだ？
六大将軍筆頭の白起です
The head of the Six Great Generals, Bai Qi.
（廉頗）
やはりな… わしも そうじゃった
Thought so. It was the same with me.
Bai Qi was a general that never risked danger.
白起は 危険を冒さぬ将であった
No matter how tasty the bait I scattered was, he would never take it.
こちらが いかに うまそうなエサを
ばらまいても 決して乗ってこず
And the more irritated I'd become, the more he would relax and dodge my assaults.
こちらがムキになれば なるほど
ヤツは力を抜き
ゆらゆらと かわしおった
（廉頗）あやつは いつでも
相手の心理が読めていたのだ
That man always read his opponent's state of mind.
いらだって 深追いしたあげくに
しっぺ返しを食らうというのが―
Getting irritated, chasing the too far, and then in the end facing retaliation was routine for Bai Qi and I.
わしと白起の定番じゃった
ハハハッ…
なぜ今 そんな話を？
Why would you tell this story now?
フッ…
なんとなくじゃが どうも―
Just a hunch, but seeing Wang Jian's leisurely retreat
悠々と下がる王翦の姿が
ふと 白起を思い出させた
suddenly reminded me of Bai Qi.
王翦が白起と同等と？
You're saying that Wang Jian is on the same level as Bai Qi?!
（廉頗）ハハハッ…
そこまでは言っておらぬが
Well, I didn't go that far.
だが 今のところ どうも
戦い方に共通するものがある
But what he just did had some resemblance to Bai Qi's fighting style.
戦い方が似ているということは…
And having a similar fighting style
近い世界が見えておるのやも
しれぬということだ
may mean they are seeing a similar world.
That plan where he appeared in the enclosed land was certainly a stroke of genius,
確かに
あの囲地に現れた策は見事でしたが
それだけでは何とも…
何しろ 白起は 正真正銘の怪物
but that alone, I feel...
At any rate, Bai Qi was a true and utter monster...
Urgent report! Urgent report!
（伝令）急報！ 急報！
（伝令）前方に敵の… 敵のあれ…
とにかく前へお急ぎを！
Up ahead, the enemy...
The enemy is...
Anyhow, you must hurry ahead!
（廉頗）野戦 攻城戦 籠城戦…
白起とは いろいろ やり合った
Field battles, castle sieges, holding castles, Bai Qi and I fought each other in all of them.
こうやって ヤツの軍の
背を追うことも何度かあったが
I chased after his army like this many times, but...
at the place he retreated to, he would always have something waiting for me that would leave me numb.
ヤツの下がった先には
決まって―
わしをシビれさせるものが
待っておったわい
例えば
こんな山の中では 知らぬ間に…
For example, in these mountains, without me knowing...
( Flags - Wang )
（廉頗）
巨大な城を築いていたりする
he would have done something like construct a gigantic castle!
Well done.
やりおる
戦略の中に 築城の手を持つ武将は
めったにいない
It's not often you see a military commander that is crafty enough to construct a castle during a maneuver.
I'm well aware now of how great your caliber is.
器の大きさを知るには十分だ
Did you perhaps construct this, predicting I would come here?
まさか
わしが来ることを読んでの築城か
（廉頗）ハハハッ… 驚いたのぅ
I am quite surprised!
So a man like you was still hidden in the shadows of the Six Great Generals, Wang Jian?!
六大将軍の陰に―
まだ うぬのような男が
隠れておったとはのぅ 王翦
A natural fortress.
確かに この戦いの地に
一番乗りしたのは王翦だったが
It certainly seems that the one that took most advantage of this battle's terrain was Wang Jian.
So in addition to that enclosed land, he found terrain of this caliber?
囲地のほかにも
これほどの地形を見つけていたのか
我々に攻城の準備はない
備えなしの攻城は 損害が激しい
We are not prepared to siege it.
And losses brought from an unprepared siege on a castle are harsh.
It's become a nearly impossible task to slay him now.
ヤツを討つのは 至難の業となった
What the hell?! Wang Jian, you bastard!
なんじゃ 王翦！ 貴様は！
（廉頗）姜燕！
（姜燕）はっ！
Jiang Yan!
Sir?
（廉頗）野営の準備だ
この砦を包囲するぞ！
Prepare to camp for the night!
Surround that fortress!
Yes, sir!
Bi
What're those guys doing?
（兵士Ａ）
何やってんだ？ あいつら
That's the Feixin Unit.
（兵士Ｂ）飛信(ひしん)隊だよ
（兵士Ｃ）
まだ隊長が戻ってこないんだってさ
Apparently their captain hasn't come back yet.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）中央軍同士の戦いは―
In the battle between the central armies,
敵の攻撃によって
秦国軍の陣形も乱れに乱れた
the enemy's attack made the State of Qin Army's formations become disordered as well.
It became a melee so chaotic that a small unit that left its formation would not be able to make it back.
一度はぐれた小隊が
元の場所へ戻れないほどの―
大混戦となったのである
（騎兵）
羌瘣(きょうかい)どのは休んでいてください
Please rest a while, Lord Qiang Lei.
O-Over there!
（昂(こう)）あっ！ あ… あれ！
（信(しん)）ウウ…
（尾平(びへい)）し… 信！
（渕(えん)）信どの！
Xin!
Lord Xin!
Captain!
（兵士）隊長！
（兵士）良かった！
Thank goodness!
Lord Xin!
（兵士）信どの！
（蒙恬(もうてん)）ハァ…
（じい）蒙恬さま
土門(どもん) 栄備(えいび) 両将軍がお待ちです
Lord Meng Tian, both generals Tu Men and Rong Bei are awaiting you.
Got it.
分かってる
There may still be pursuers!
（壁）まだ追っ手が
かかっているかもしれん！
Keep up the pace!
足を休めるな！
気を抜かずに進むんだ！
Stay focused and march!
General Wang Jian, what are you?
王翦将軍… あなたは何だ？
何を考えておられるのだ？
I can't believe you would purposefully set us up as decoys...
（壁）わざわざ 私たちを囮(おとり)にして
そして 多くの兵を犠牲に…
only to simply run away when a great amount of soldiers have been sacrificed.
ただ逃げたとは思えぬ
Forget Yan Jiang, I don't understand anything about you...
姜燕のことといい
あなたは分からぬことだらけだ
It's rare to find a military commander with the ability to erect a castle.
（廉頗）
築城の能力を持つ武将は稀(まれ)じゃ
（廉頗）あの六大将軍の中でも
白起くらいじゃった
I think even among the Six Great Generals, it was just Bai Qi.
白起の守りには
よく苦しめられたが
I had a lot of hardships against Bai Qi's defenses,
これも見劣りせぬ 大した出来じゃ
but this is by no means inferior to those.
It seems that it may be true that the depth of his tactics and his uniqueness are on par with Bai Qi's.
確かに 軍略の深さ 特異さは
白起と同等なのかもしれぬ
じゃが
これは だいぶ違うであろう 王翦
But Wang Jian's also pretty different.
At the position of Vice General,
副将のぶんざいで…
あやつは 己をこの戦において
秦国軍の最上と捉えておる
in this battle, he sees himself the top of the State of Qin Army.
That's what his behavior tells me.
あの挙動が それを物語っておる
Indeed...
確かに
With that fortress, it has become more difficult to defeat Wang Jian but...
あの砦で
王翦を討つのは難しくなったが
逆の見方をするなら 我々は
ヤツをここに封じることになった
taking things from another perspective, we've also sealed him here.
If the principal of the State of Qin Army's power in this war is in its two Vice Generals,
こたびの秦国軍の主力が
左右の副将軍とするなら―
that is a major blow.
これは大きな痛手
更に 秦国軍としては―
And for the State of Qin Army,
最悪の事態への対処の手も
半分 消された
their ability to cope with worst-case scenarios has been cut in half.
Though I'm sure he's realized that!
ヤツが
それに気づいていないはずがない
My country will require men that are powerful in battle like you.
（王翦）私の国は うぬのような
戦の強い男を必要としているのだ
It seems that Wang Jian is lacking in one area as a military commander, don't you think?
王翦は 武将として
何か欠落した部分がありそうですね
A big one!
（廉頗）大きくな
大きく ゆがんでおる
He's very warped.
Wang Jian, I understand the reason why you never let the light of the sun touch you ever since the age of King Zhao.
王翦… 貴様が 昭王(しょうおう)のころより―
これまで日の光を
当てられなかった訳が分かったぞい
A military commander that puts himself as number one will not be given trust.
己を第一とする武将は
信頼が置けぬのだ
いかに戦が強かろうと それでは
誰も貴様を英雄とは認めぬ
No matter how powerful he is in war, no one will recognize him as a hero.
You and I stand on different paths.
貴様と わしらとは
違う道に立っている
There is no need to deny it.
あえて否定はせぬが
王翦… 興味も うせたわ
Wang Jian, my interest in you has vanished!
Jiang Yan! I'm leaving this place to you!
姜燕 この場は任せたぞ
どのみち この戦場から
王翦は姿を消したも同然
Either way, if he's here, Wang Jian might as well be gone.
I doubt he'll make a move any time soon.
しばらくは 動くことはなかろう
（姜燕）それでは 殿…
What will you do, my lord?
I'm going back to basics.
基本に戻る
戦は大将を殺してなんぼ
In a war, you kill the other general.
出来の悪い 古い顔見知りに
引導を渡しに行くかのぅ
I'll be going to perform the last rites for an old mediocre acquaintance.
この戦 明日で終わらせるぞ 姜燕
（姜燕）ははっ！
We'll be ending this war tomorrow, Jiang Yan!
Yes, sir!
（蒙驁(もうごう)）フォフォフォ…
土門と栄備から
ひと言あったようじゃのぅ
Sounds like Tu Men and Rong Bei had something to say to you.
はい… １発ずつ殴られました
Yes. They hit me once each.
（蒙驁）フォフォフォ…
それで済んで良かったのぅ
You should be glad that's all it was.
So, for what reason did you call me, Great General?
して 何用でしょうか？ 大将軍
Enough of that. This is a conversation between a grandpa and his grandson.
よせよせ！ 今ここにいるのは
じじいと孫の２人だけじゃ
恬 こっちへ
（蒙恬）どうしたの？ じいちゃん
This way, Tian.
What's going on, Grandpa? This isn't like you.
いつもと違う…
こういうノリは好きじゃない
I don't like this atmosphere.
（蒙驁）まあ そう言うな 恬よ
Hey, don't say that, Tian.
It's strange, but when you get to be my age, you figure out a few things.
不思議と この年になると
分かることがあるのじゃ
死力を尽くす戦いが
近づいているとな
Like a battle where you'll have to fight with all your strength.
だから らしくないって
Seriously, this isn't like you.
The White Elder's style is to not get worked up or be reckless, right?
“気負わず ムチャせず”が
白老の戦い方でしょう
フォフォフォ… いつもならな
Normally, yes.
だが 今度だけは…
But this time...
even I cannot retreat.
わしも ひくことはない
（尾平）信 お前… その傷…
（昂）ほ… 骨まで
Xin, you... those wounds...
A-All the way to the bone...!
ヘヘッ… ちょっと深そうだな
Looks like it's pretty deep.
Wait there. I'll bring medicine.
待ってろ　薬を取ってくる
And you dirty louts, get outside!
小汚いお前らは外へ出ろ
信の傷が悪化する
You'll make Xin's wounds worse.
（尾平）えっ？ ホントか？
Huh? Really?!
Get outta here, everybody! Scatter, scatter!
離れろ！ みんな 散れ 散れ！
（向(こう)）ハァ… やっぱり
残っちゃったな あのときの傷
I knew it... It left a mark... That wound...
（政）まだ傷が痛むのか？
（向）えっ？
Is your wound still bothering you?
N-No!
あっ ち… 違います！
痛みは もう全然！
The pain is completely gone...
（政）うん？ “痛みは”？
The pain...
ウワッ！
Look, Xiang.
（政）見ろ 向
（向）えっ？
These are scars I obtained during my little brother's rebellion.
（政）弟の反乱のときについた傷だ
醜いか？
（向）め… めっそうもありません
Are they ugly?
Of course not! Absolutely not!
そ… そんな…
（政）ウソだ
You're lying.
I'm not lying! I swear it!
ウソじゃありません 決して！
They're proof that you survived, your majesty!
大王さまが生きてこられた証しです
だから 醜いなんて思いません
So I could never think of them as ugly!
だったら 俺も お前の傷を
醜いなんて みじんも思わない
In that case, I don't think either yours nor my own scars are the least bit ugly.
あっ…
（政）信じるか？
Do you believe me?
は… はい　信じます
Y-Yes. I believe you... I believe you...
（向）信じます…
（羌瘣）我慢しろ
（信）ンンッ… それ 何だ？
Endure it.
What is that?!
A secret medicine handed down through my clan's village.
私の村に伝わる秘薬だ
特別な薬草で調合して作った
You make it by mixing special medicinal plants.
I've been gathering it during the march.
行軍の途中 ずっと集めてきたが
できたのは この貝殻１つ分だ
But I've only managed to make enough to fill one of these shells.
Use something important like that on yourself, you idiot!
そんな貴重な物(もん) 自分に使えよ バカ
Chu Shui told me you overdid it a lot out there!
お前が相当ムリしたって
楚水(そすい)が言ってたぞ
私は お前みたいにヘマはしない
（信）アアッ！
I didn't make any blunders like the ones you did.
（信）ウウ… あんがとな
Thanks.
（信）うん？ な… 何だよ？
W-What?
That Lun Hu...
（羌瘣）輪虎(りんこ)ってヤツ…
（信）うん？
（羌瘣）
ひょっとして 強かったか？
Was he perhaps really strong?
えっ？
強かったなんてもんじゃねえよ
He wasn't just strong.
Well, he wasn't a monster like Pang Nuan,
まあ 龐煖(ほうけん)みてえな怪物じゃねえが
そこいらの武将とはワケが違う
but he was different from those other generals around there.
With all the battles he's been in, he's been at the verge of death...
あいつは戦を重ねて 死線を…
限界を何度も超えてきた男の
強さを持ってた
He pushed his limited countless times and became incredibly strong for it.
And I also...
そして 俺も…
Uh, I'm not sure how to say it, but...
（信）
いや うまくは言えねえんだが
I feel like I overcame one of my limitations, too.
俺も１コ 自分の限界ってやつを
超えた気がする
なるほど　そういうことか
I see. So that's what it is.
Even though he's this beaten up, his presence is a size large than it's been up until now.
こんなにボロボロなのに―
こいつの気配は 今までよりも
ひと回り大きくなっている
I know saying that is kinda weird for a guy who failed to take down his enemy...
（信）…て 討ち損じたヤツが
言うのも変だけどな ヘヘッ！
Well, look. We had all those sacrifices but we failed.
（信）まあ 見てろ
すげえ犠牲を出したってのに
しくじっちまった
But I'm definitely going to take responsibility for it!
そのケジメは きっちり つけるぜ
次で必ず あいつをこの手で討つ
Next time, I swear I'll take him down with my own hands!
Then get some rest and recover.
だったら しっかり寝て 回復しろ
Until your fever goes down, you are in no shape to fight.
熱が下がらなければ
戦いどころではない
With that secret medicine you gave me, I'll be back to normal in one night.
お前の秘薬を塗ったんだ
ひと晩で元どおりさ
（羌瘣）それはない
No, you won't.
ヘヘッ…
そんなに都合よくはいかねえか
Not that convenient, eh?
What? You gonna sleep here?
なんだ お前　ここで寝るのか？
That medicine is really potent.
さっきの薬は効き目が強い
たまに拒絶反応が出る
Sometimes you have a strong reaction to it.
So I'm going to keep a watch over you for a while.
（羌瘣）
だから しばらく ここで様子を見る
（信）…と言いつつ
本当は俺と一緒にいたいと
Right, you just wanna be with me, right?
Right, I'll just be leaving.
（羌瘣）やっぱり戻る
具合が悪くなったら 勝手に死ね
If you're not doing well, feel free to die.
（信）ああっ！ ウソだって ウソ！
I was kidding! It was a joke!
（王賁(おうほん)）ンッ！
Once this war ends, we won't have arguments like this for a while either, I guess.
（信）この戦が終わったら―
こういうやり取りも
しばらくできねえな
Ah well. It'll be a bit lonely.
しゃあねえけど 寂しくなるぜ
（羌瘣）先の心配より あしただ
Instead of worrying about that, think about tomorrow.
この戦は
きっと簡単には終わらない
This war definitely won't be ending easily.
（信）ああ… そうだな
Yeah. You're right about that.
ああ… やっぱ こうして見ると
ケガ人ばっかだな
Yeah. After getting a good look around, we really do have a lot of injured.
（松左(しょうさ)）そりゃ そうだろう
今日で何日目だ？
Well, yeah. How many days does this make?
う～ん… ケガ人だらけも道理か
だけど いちばんヤバイのは信だ
I guess there's good reason for all these injured.
But the one in the most danger is Xin.
He got a fever from those wounds, and if he can't get out of bed for another two or three days...
あの傷は熱も出てたし
２～３日は起き上がれねえと…
Who was that!? It's first thing in the morning, what're you...
こら！ 誰だ！ 朝っぱら…
オス！ 尾平
'Sup, Wei Ping.
し… 信！ 大丈夫なのか？ お前
Xin!
Are you okay?
As you can see.
このとおりよ
And... check this out!
…んで このとおりよ！
（松左）おお！
（兵士）さすが隊長！
That's our captain!
Awesome!
And even your bones were cut!
But you really are all better, right, Xin?
でも ホントによく治ったね 信
正直 もう右手はダメかと思ったよ
Honestly, I didn't think your right hand would be healed yet.
Ya see, Qiang Lei had this awesome medicine he gave me.
羌瘣がな
１コしかねえ すげえ薬を
くれたんだ
It's not just the effect of the medicine.
（羌瘣）薬の効用だけじゃない
Qiang Lei?!
（信）羌瘣…
（羌瘣）薬の力が半分
The power of the medicine was half.
The other half was your nonsensical recuperative power.
（羌瘣）あと半分は お前の
そのでたらめな回復力のおかげだ
あいつ…
She...
Qiang Lei!
（信）羌瘣！
Today, we're really gonna crush the State of Wei Army!
今日こそ 魏国軍をぶっつぶすぞ！
しゃー！ こっから仕切り直しだ！
All right!
Now for a fresh start!
Let's beat the shit outta them!
ぶちかますぞ！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
（輪虎）ハハハッ…
朝から元気だな 向こうは
The other side looks spirited first thing in the morning.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）ここ流尹(るい)平野での
戦いが始まって６日
This is the 6th day since the beginning of this battle on the Liuyin Plains.
It has been about two and a half months since the State of Qin Army sortied for the attack on Shanyang.
秦国軍が山陽(さんよう)攻略戦に出陣して
およそ２か月半がたっていた
秦国軍は
これまで16の城を奪ったが
Up to this point, the State of Qin Army has captured sixteen castles,
目的は あくまで その奥の―
but their goal is ultimately to capture that all-important military stronghold deep within Wei, Shanyang.
軍事的最重要拠点 山陽を
手にすることである
Unless they can crush the State of Wei Army that has been sent to defend it,
山陽を守るために出てきた
この魏国軍を撃破せねば―
今回の攻略戦そのものが
失敗に終わるのである
this war itself will end in failure.
The defending State of Wei,
守る魏国
the attacking State of Qin, and...
攻める秦国　そして…
それを見守る諸外国の強敵たち
the formidable foes of the other states, watching over it.
The great and various thoughts and feelings from all across China
中国全土のさまざま かつ
巨大な思い 思惑が―
are all concentrated on Shanyang.
山陽一点に集中していた
（楚水）信どの？
Lord Xin?
ハハハッ… さすがに見えねえか
Guess he can't see me.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）そして その中心で
戦いに命を懸ける男たちは―
And at the center of all of this, the men risking their lives in battle
sensed something mysterious.
不思議なことに察していた
フン… やはり そうか
I thought so.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）これから 山陽大攻略戦
その最後の日の 幕が開けることを
The curtain now opens on the final day of the war to capture Shanyang!
Preview
The Hour of
Conclusion
End